

# **INFORMATION**

Xiaoya (Shirley) Lyu https://shirleylyu.com shirley.lyu.xiaoya@gmail.com

### **PROFILE**

I am a multidisciplinary designer hoping to improve communities through product and education. As a **product designer**, I specialize in lifestyle products, UI/UX, furniture, and spatial experience design. As an **instructional designer**, I am passionate about designing playful and effective learning experiences for informal education.

## RECOGNITION

### SIT Furniture Design Award

Global

• Skate | 2023 Winner in Other Chairs

### **ArtCenter Gallery**

Pasadena, CA

- Skate | Furniture | 2022 Fall
- Refugia | Spatial | 2022 Summer
- Sunrise | Speaker | 2021 Fall

### LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Proficient

### **EDUCATION**

## Teachers College Columbia University | Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2024

New York, NY

Master of Art in Instructional Technology and Media

## ArtCenter College of Design | Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2023

Pasadena, CA

Bachelor of Science in Product Design Minor in Designmatters Social Innovation

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**NORY, Inc.** | Feb. 2024 - Mar. 2024

Part-Time STEM Curriculum Developer | New York, USA

- Developed STEM curriculum through prototyping and lesson planning
- Developed a teacher support system

Teachers College | Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Course Assistant | New York, USA

- Hosted workshops on Figma and UIUX prototyping.
- Guided students on applying Figma to mobile learning design.

**Yang Design** | May 2021 - Aug. 2021

Design Internship | Shanghai, China

- Conducted brand and trend research through user interviews
- Developed concept design and CMF
- Showcased design results to clients

## PROJECT HIGHLIGHT

### Bernhardt Sponsored Project | Aug. 2022 - Dec. 2022

Mobility Furniture Design

- Designed a mobile office chair for collaborative open spaces
- Engendered to meet Bernhardt's manufacturing requirements
- Modeled and visualized for production and made sample piece

### **SKILLS**

### Software

Photoshop | Illustrator | Indesign | Keyshot | Figma | Rhino | Solidworks Gravity Sketch | Twinmotion | Unreal Engine | Microsoft Office

### Design skills

Product Design | Instructional Design | Spatial Experience Design | UI/UX CMF | Design Research | Prototyping | Manufacturing | Visualization

### Frontend Development

HTML | CSS | Javascript | React | Bootstrap